Guide to the Department of Manuscripts and Archives, Fortunoff Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Manuscripts and Archives, Fortunoff Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies records
1944-2017
RU 1150
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
46.85
The records consist of administrative files, correspondence, and survivor testimonies from the Fortunoff Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies.
[Main entry organizational]
[Additional creator]
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files, correspondence, and survivor testimonies from the Fortunoff Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies.
Biographical / Historical
The Fortunoff Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies began as a New Haven, Connecticut community project called the Holocaust Survivors Film Project (HSFP). The HSFP was founded by Laurel Vlock, a television journalist and Dori Laub, a psychologist and child survivor of the Holocaust. William Rosenberg, the president of the New Haven chapter of the Farband, a Zionist labor organization, was also instrumental in the creation of the project. One of the first four survivors whose gave testimony to the project was married to Geoffrey Hartman, a professor of English and Comparative Literatures at Yale University and a child survivor who escaped Germany on a Kindertransport. He was instrumental in bringing the HSFP's testimonies to Yale in 1981, where it was established as part of Manuscripts and Archives. An endowment by Alan Fortunoff permanently established the archive, which was renamed in his honor to the Fortunoff Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies.
The Fortunoff Archive records testimonies of survivors, witnesses and bystanders of Nazi persecution. This includes Jewish and non-Jewish witnesses, Sinti and Roma survivors, individuals hidden during the war, those who escaped before the end of the war, resisters and partisans, liberators, and aid workers who served in the DP camps after the war. The Fortunoff interview methodology emphasizes giving agency to the survivor or witness to tell and structure their story as they wish. In addition to recording testimonies in New Haven and other cities, the Fortunoff Archive formed affiliate projects in other states and countries, where interviewers trained by archive staff recorded testimonies and sent a copy to the Fortunoff Archive for preservation and use in teaching and research. Over time, 37 affiliate projects were established, including projects in Germany, France, Israel, Belgium, Slovakia and many more. The Fortunoff Archive also holds conferences and other events related to testimony and its impact on Holocaust and Genocide Studies.
[Personal name]; [Organizational name]
- Records, 1944–2017; Accession 2018-A-0014
  Conditions Governing Access
  Records from Box 20 are restricted until January 1, 2093. All other records are restricted until January 1, 2053.
  - Affiliate projects
    - United States
      - Arizona Project, 1990–1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Atlantic County, 1986–2000 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
      - Baltimore Jewish Council, 1986–2000 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
      - Baltimore Jewish Council, bibilography, 1990–1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Brookline, Mass., 1991–1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Baltimore Jewish Council, Deli Strummer, 2000 June–2000 September (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Cincinnati Project, 1988–2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Cleveland Project, 1982–1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Columbus, Ohio Project, 1985–1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Dallas Memorial Center for Hollocaust Studies, 1983–2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Houston Project, 1990–2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Illinois Project, 1982–1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Chicago Problems, 1986–1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Kansas City, 1985–2000 (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
      - Kean College of New Jersey, 1983–2003 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Second Generation of Long Island, 1982–1997 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Maine Holocaust Human Rights Center of Maine., 1985–2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Milwaukee-The Generation After, 1988–2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - New York City Holocaust Memorials, 1990–2001 (Box 1, Folder 29-31)
      - New York City Holocaust Memorial, 1990–2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - New York City Holocaust Memorial, Commission, 1985–1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - New York City Holocaust Commission-Blumenfeld, 1984 January–1984 April (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - New York City Holocaust Memorial-Publicity, 1989–1999 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - New York Preservation, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - New York Preservation: Responses, 1999–2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - North Shore Holocaust Center, 1986–2008 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - North Shore P.A. lists, 1989–2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Ramapo College, NJ- correspondence, 1982–2016 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
      - Ramapo College, NJ- accession Lists, 1990–2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - San Antonio Project, 1985–2000 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
      - Second Generation of Westchester, 1984–1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Selfhelp, 1985–1994 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
      - UCLA 1939 Club Project, 1982–2000 (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
      - University of Michigan, Dearborn, Bolkosky, SID, 1981–2007 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Detroit Taping Project, Bolkosky S., 1981–2007 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Argentina Project, 1988–2001 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Bolivia-Spitzer/Dartmouth, 1995–2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - France
      - France Project, 1990–2002 (Box 2, Folder 23-25)
      - Abramowicz, 1989-1990 (Box 2a, Folder 1)
      - Ecole des Hautes Etudes, 1992-1993 (Box 2a, Folder 3)
      - Fondation pour la Memoire de la Deportation, 1993-1996 (Box 2a, Folder 4)
      - Klarsfeld/European tapings, 1985-1992 (Box 2a, Folder 5)
    - Gypsy Project, 1986–1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Vancouver, British Columbia/Krell, 1983–2014 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
    - Czech Republic/Prague, 1995–1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - German Taping, 1989–1997 (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
    - Berlin Project, 1994–2005 (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
    - German Project-Frankfurt Conference, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Athens, Greece, 1988–1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Athens, Greece- Receipts, 1944–1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Greece-Salonika, 1992–1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Greece-Salonika-Financial, 1993 June–1993 August (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Israel, 1982–1997 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - AMCHA Center, 1993–1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Israel
      - Haifa/Ray D. Wolfe Center, 1996–2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Taping Project-Liason Report-BH, 1983–1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Preliminary Accession Lists, 1991–2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Ravensbruck Group, Tel Aviv University, 1997–1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Israel Trip, 1982–1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - USHMM Ukraine, Belarus, Poland, 1993–2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - USHMM Israel, 1990–2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Words and Images, 1994–2017 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Slovakia, 1994–2001 (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
    - Slovak Project/IREX Grant, 1994–1999 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Yugoslavia- Almuli, Jasa, 1988–1995 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
    - Yugoslavia-Belgrade, 1994–1998 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
    - Beyrak, Nathan Faxes, 1991–1995 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
    - Beyrak, Nathan Faxes, 1993–1997 (Box 4, Folder 1-10)
    - Beyrak, Nathan Correspondence, 1998–2001 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
    - Beyrak, Nathan Database, 1994 September (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - English Project, 1985–2011 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - Belgium- Fondation Auschwitz, 1990–2004 (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
  - Barcodes
    - Master boxes 125-150, 2001–2005 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Master boxes 1-25, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Master boxes 26-50, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Master boxes 51-75, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Master boxes 76-100, 1998 (Box 4a, Folder 1)
    - Master boxes 101-125, 1998 (Box 4a, Folder 2)
    - Master boxes 126-150, 1998–2000 (Box 4a, Folder 3)
    - Master boxes 155, 2003 (Box 4a, Folder 4)
    - Duplicate boxes 1-25, 1998 June–1998 October (Box 4a, Folder 5)
    - Duplicate boxes 51-75, 1998 June–1998 September (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Duplicate boxes 76-100, 1998 June–1998 September (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Duplicate boxes 101-125, 1998 June 26 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Duplicate boxes 126-150, 1998 June–1998 September (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Duplicate boxes 151-175, 1998 June 26 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Duplicate boxes 175-200, 1998 June 29 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Duplicate boxes 201-225, 1998 June 30 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Duplicate boxes 251, 1998 July–1998 October (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Duplicate boxes 226-250, 1998 July (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Duplicate boxes 276-300, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Duplicate boxes 301-325, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Duplicate boxes 326-350, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Duplicate boxes 351-375, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Duplicate boxes 376-400, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Duplicate boxes 401-425, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Duplicate boxes 426-450, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Duplicate boxes 451-475, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Duplicate boxes 476-500, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Duplicate boxes 501-525, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Duplicate boxes 526-550, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Duplicate boxes 551-575, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Duplicate boxes 576-600, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Duplicate boxes 601-625, 1998–1999 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Duplicate boxes 626-650, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Duplicate boxes 651-675, 1999–2000 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Duplicate boxes 676-700, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Duplicate boxes 700-725, 2001 July 24 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Duplicate boxes 726-750, 2001–2002 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Duplicate boxes 759-780, 2002–2003 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Duplicate boxes 781, 2003–2005 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Restoration master boxes 1-25, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Restoration master boxes 26-50, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Restoration master boxes 51-75, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Restoration master boxes 76-100, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Restoration master boxes 81, 88, 91, 114, 2001 July 24 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Restoration master boxes 101-125, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Restoration master boxes 101-125, 2001 August 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Restoration master boxes 126-150, 2001 October 24 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Restoration master boxes 151-175, 2001 October 24 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Restoration master boxes 176-200, 2001 October 24 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Restoration master boxes 201-205, 2001–2002 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Restoration master boxes 226-255, 2002 April–2002 July (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Restoration master boxes 256, 2005 February–2005 May (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Restoration master boxes 275-300, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Restoration master boxes 301-325, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Restoration master boxes 1-25, 2000–2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Restoration master boxes 26-50, 2000 June 20–2000 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Restoration master boxes 51-75, 2000 June 20 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Restoration submaster boxes 76-100, 2000–2002 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Restoration submaster boxes 101-125, 2000–2002 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Restoration submaster boxes 126-150, 2002 March 28 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Restoration submaster boxes 256, 2005 February–2005 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Restoration submaster boxes 275-300, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Restoration submaster boxes 300-325, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Use copy boxes 1-25, 2002 June 20 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Use copy boxes 26-50, 2002 June 21 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Use copy boxes 51-75, 2002 June 24 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Use copy boxes 76-100, 2002 April 24 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Use copy boxes 101-125, 2002 June 26 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Use copy boxes 126-150, 2002 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Use copy boxes 151-175, 2002 July 9 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Use copy boxes 176-200, 2002 July 10 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Use copy boxes 201-225, 2002 July 12 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Use copy boxes 226-258, 2002–2004 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Updated barcode sheets, 2005–2010 (Box 7, Folder 2-10)
    - Barcode sheets-problems, 2003 June 30 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Barcodes- additions, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Conferences and events
    - "An Evening With Claude Lanzermann" poster, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts from the 1981 conference (Box 7, Folder 13-16)
    - Inauguration of the Video Archives for Holocaust Testimonies at Yale poster, 1982 November 15 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - "Knowing and Not Knowing", 1982 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "The Educational and Research Uses of the Yale Video Archive and Education and the Holocaust", 1983–1984 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Viewing of testimonies event poster, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - "Education and the Holocaust: New Responsibilities and Cooperative Ventures," papers, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - "Education and the Holocaust: New Responsibilities and Cooperative Ventures," Public Relations and Publicity, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - "Testimonies" conference poster, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - "Testimonies" conference poster, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Papers and Curriculum Vitae, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
    - Tenth anniversary donations, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 23-26)
    - Tenth anniversary fundraiser, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Tenth anniversary patron dinner photographs, 1992 December 7 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Tenth anniversary Sterling Memorial Library exhibit, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - "The Future of Memory" conference poster, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - "Searching for Memory and Justice: Holocaust and Apartheid"
      - General, 1998 February 8 (Box 7, Folder 30-33)
      - Contact sheets, 1998 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Speaker Releases, 1998 February (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Photographs, 1998 February 8 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Planning, 1997–1999 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Poster, 1998 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - "The Contribution of Oral Testimony to Holocaust and Genocide Studies"
      - General, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Arrangements, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Chronology, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Papers, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Invitations, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Meals, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Personal announcements, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Poster, 2002 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Press (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
      - Printing, 2002 September (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Promotional materials, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Seating plan, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Speakers, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
      - Web exhibit, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Web exhibit: Permissions - Publishers, 2002–2003 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Testimony Across the Disciplines"
      - General, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Pamphlets, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Posters, 2007 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Printing, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Publicity and press, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "Achievements and Challenges: 1982-2012"
      - General, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
      - Food, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Hotel, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Meals, hotels, physical facilities, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Pamphlets, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Posters, 2012 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Printing, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Program, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Publicity and press, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Wiesel, Elie, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence
    - A-Ak, 1982–2009 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Al-Am, 1982–2003 (Box 8, Folder 32-33)
    - An-Az, 1982–2010 (Box 8, Folder 34-36)
    - Accession lists, 1979–1993 (Box 8, Folder 37-38)
    - New England Region AHO, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Association of Holocaust Organizations, 1986–1996 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Allentown Project, 1983–1984 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - American Gathering: Until 1990, 1983–1985 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - B, 1985–1996 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Ba-Beg, 1982–2009 (Box 8, Folder 45-46)
    - Beh-Bie, 1980–2008 (Box 8, Folder 47-48)
    - Bif-Bo 1983-2009 (Box 8, Folder 49-50)
    - Bp-Bz, 1983–2004 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Baltimore Hebrew U. Library, 1991 April 22–1991 April 30 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Bergen-Belsen Memorial, 1989–2007 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Bergen-Belsen Memorial, 2002–2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bergen-Belsen Memorial JWR Trip, 2004–2006 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Borrowed books, 1990–2009 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Blaustein, 1981–2007 (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
    - C-Cd, 1974–2014 (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
    - Ce-Cl, 1982–2014 (Box 9, Folder 21-23)
    - Cm-Col, 1984–2013 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Com-Cz, 1982–2014 (Box 9, Folder 25-26)
    - Canadian Friends of Massuah, 1991–1993 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Canadian Project, 1981–1985 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Community Information Workshop, 1983 November 28–1983 December 12 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Conference of Jewish Material Claims Against Germany, Inc., 2010–2011 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Connecticut Holocaust Education Network, 1995–1996 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Councils office, 1990–1995 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Course outlines, 1982–2009 (Box 9, Folder 34-36)
    - D-Dej, 1983–2006 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Dek-Dh, 1983–2010 (Box 9, Folder 38-39)
    - Di-Dz, 1971–2001 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Department of Justice/OSI, 2002 May–2002 December (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Development, 1984–1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Development: endowment campaign, 1998–1999 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - E-Ee, 1983–2003 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Ef-Ef, 1982–2016 (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
    - Education Committee, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Equipment inventory, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - F-Fh, 1983–2007 (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
    - Fi-Fk, 1982–2015 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Fl-Frh, 1982–2004 (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
    - Fri-Fz, 1982–2015 (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
    - Facing History and Ourselves- correspondence, 1977–1999 (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
    - Facing History and Ourselves- publication materials, 1987–2000 (Box 10, Folder 22-23)
    - Facing History and Ourselves- loans, 1982–1989 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Facing History and Ourselves -Strom, Margot, 1983–1990 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Fortunoff, 1987–2016 (Box 10, Folder 27-29)
    - G-Gg, 1981–2015 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Gh-Gol, 1982–2017 (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
    - Gom-Gz, 1982–2014 (Box 11, Folder 6-8)
    - Garland Publishing Guide Vol. I, 1988–1998 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Giamatti, A.B., 1980–1989 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Ha-Hb, 1982–2013 (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
    - Hc-Hh, 1984–2010 (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
    - Hi-Holm, 1983–2012 (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
    - Holo-Hz, 1979–2015 (Box 11, Folder 19-20)
    - I, 1982–2005 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Interfaith Council on the Holocaust, 1991–1995 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - isurvived.org, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - J, 1983–2015 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - J, 1983–2015 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Joint Distribution Committee, 1990–1996 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Joods Historisch Museum, 1988–1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - K-Kd, 1982–2015 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
    - Ke-Kn, 1983–2014 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
    - Ko-Kq, 1983–2010 (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
    - Kr-Kr, 1983–2014 (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
    - La-Leg, 1983–2014 (Box 12, Folder 14-15)
    - Leh-Lh, 1983–2009 (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
    - Li-Liz, 1982–2014 (Box 12, Folder 18-20)
    - Levin, Richard, 1993–2002 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - ARL-Preservation Stats, 2003–2006 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Library, 1985–1988 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - M-Man, 1982–2001 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Mar-Mc, 1982–2014 (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
    - Md-Mh, 1983–2011 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
    - Mi-Mill, 1982–2004 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Miln-Mk, 1982–2015 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Ml-Mz, 1982–2011 (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
    - Marriage Council of Philadelphia, 1986–1993 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Masters, 1988–2007 (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
    - MS&A/Liscensing Agreement for Moving Images, 1986–1994 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - N-Nb, 1982–2003 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Nc-Nf, 1982–2012 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Ng-Nz, 1983–2010 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - National Center for Jewish Film, 1984–1998 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - NEH Grant Proposal, 1982 November 5 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - New Haven Jewish Federation, 1985–2002 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - New Haven Memorial Concert, 1986–1987 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - New Haven Symphony, 1987 April 27 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Newsday, 1994–1997 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Newsletter- spring/summer, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Newsletter, 1990–2003 (Box 13, Folder 24-28)
    - O, 1982–2017 (Box 13, Folder 29-30)
    - Poetics Today, 2005 March 11 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Pre-interview question forms- blank, Undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Preservation, 1982–1997 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Psychoanalytic Inquiry, 1982–1989 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - P-Per, 1982–2006 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Pes-Pin, 1982–2003 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Pio-Pq, 1982–2004 (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
    - Pr-Pt, 1983–2013 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Pu-Q, 1984–2002 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - R-Res, 1982–2002 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
    - Rev-Rl, 1982–2012 (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
    - Rm-Rose, 1983–2015 (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
    - Rosh-Rz, 1982–2013 (Box 14, Folder 14-15)
    - Raoul Wallenberg Project, 1990–1993 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Red Cross- International Tracing Service, 1991–1992 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Sa-Sb, 1982–2014 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
    - Sc-Sd, 1982–2015 (Box 15, Folder 7-9)
    - Se-Sha, 1983–2013 (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
    - Shb-Sie, 1982–2005 (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
    - Sif-Sm, 1982–2007 (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
    - Sn-Sta, 1982–2015 (Box 15, Folder 16-17)
    - Stb-Sz, 1982–2007 (Box 15, Folder 18-20)
    - SAMMA
      - AVPS, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - Data Storage/IT, 2006–2010 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Front Porch Digital, 2010 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Odai, 1998–2012 (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Training (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Schmidt, Benno C., 1986–1992 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Scholars Conference, 1987–1994 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Second Generation, 1983–1985 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Shoah, 1997 June (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Slovakia, 2000–2003 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Solicitations, 1982–1984 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Survivors- Maps & Directions to Audio Visual Center, 1983–1995 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - T-Tg, 1983–2014 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Th-To, 1983–2003 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Td-Tz, 1985–2015 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Telecommunications, 1982–2007 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - U-Miscellaneous, 1982–2012 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - United States Holocaust Memorial Council, 1991–2006 (Box 16, Folder 9-14)
    - V, 1983–2003 (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
    - W-Wag, 1985–1999 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Wah-Wb, 1982–2014 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - We-We, 1983–2015 (Box 16, Folder 19-20)
    - Wf-Wz, 1982–2008 (Box 16, Folder 21-22)
    - Westport Federation, 1988–1995 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Wiesel, E., 1981–2013 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Y, 1982–2003 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Yale Correspondence, 1985–1992 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Yale Judaic Studies, 1981–1995 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Z-Miscellaneous, 1983–2014 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Financial and administrative files
    - Financial files